Maxime Faget Papers
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
Maxime Faget Papers
1930s-2004
1943-1995
Faget, Maxime
2014-0001
33 linear feet (62 boxes)
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
Personal papers documenting Maxime Faget's careers during his lifetime. The materials mostly cover his career in the US Navy, in NACA, and NASA spanning 53 years.
Biographical Sketch
Maxime Faget was born on August 26, 1921, in Stannis Creek, British Honduras (now Belize) and died on October 9, 2004, in Houston, Texas. Dr. Faget was married to the former Nancy Carastro of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. They lived in Dickinson, Texas, with their four children, Ann Lee, Carol Lee, Nanette, and Guy. After graduating from Louisiana State University, Faget served in the Submarine Service of the United States Navy during World War II. During his lifetime, Faget worked as a United States government employee, first at the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA) and then later as one of the founding employees of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA). Faget was on the design team for the Mercury, Gemini, Apollo, and Space Shuttle vehicles and held several key patents for both Mercury and Shuttle.
After his retirement from government service, Faget went on to found the company Space Industries. He began Space Industries, Inc. with the goal of placing a commercially operated space station in orbit. This project, named the Industrial Space Facility, was proceeding well until the disaster of Space Shuttle Challenger. After the Challenger disaster, resistance from Congress caused several key financial backers to pull out, effectively ending the viability of a commercial space venture for the 1980s and 1990s. After the disaster, Space Industries first merged with the Calspan Corporation and later with General Dynamics Corporation. It no longer exists as an independent entity.
Faget received many awards during his lifetime, including being inducted into the Space Hall of Fame and the National Inventors Hall of Fame and being elected to the National Academy of Engineering. Faget received the Arthur S. Flemming Award in 1960. He was presented the Golden Plate Award in 1961 by the Academy of Achievement. In 1963, he was awarded the NASA Medal for Outstanding Leadership, and in 1965, he was given the Award of Loyola. Faget received an honorary Doctorate of Engineering from the University of Pittsburgh in March 1966. He was an active member of the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. Faget died in 2004....
Scope and Contents of the Records
The first series of archived material consists of materials related to Faget's time as an employee of the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA). Series 2 through 8 cover materials related to Faget's time at the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), broken down by major mission headings. Series 9 contains materials related to Faget's naval service during World War II and includes retirement materials from his naval retirement in 1981. Series 10 contains general biographical information about Faget and includes personal letters, autobiographies, oral histories, personal interviews, and obituaries. Series 11 through 14 contain presentations, handbooks, and miscellany not directly related to any specific NACA, NASA, or Space Industries projects covered in other series. Series 15 encompasses the many honors and awards Faget received in his lifetime. Series 16 contains technical reports written or co-authored by Faget. Series 17 covers Faget's time at Space Industries, and Series 18 concerns the Industrial Space Facility, the major project of Space Industries in the 1980s and early 1990s. Series 19 through 22 contain other media, such as photographs, slides, newspaper clippings, magnetic tape, and floppy discs. Materials from the floppy discs have been printed out and may be found in Box 47, Folder 2 at the end of the collection. Series 23 through 25 contain oversized items, such as scrapbooks, legal sized items, periodicals, 35 mm film, and glass slides.
Arrangement
The records of the Maxime Faget collection have been arranged in series by subject matter and document type.
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Faget, Maxime; Faget, Max; Forrestal, James; Williams, Walt; Cooper, Gordon; Gilruth, Robert; Allen, Joseph; Harleston, Hugh, Jr.; Faget, Nancy; Griffin, Gerry; Branch, Angela; Daniel, L. R., JR.; Byrd, James A.; Benson, Charles; Huffington, Roy; Dunwoody. W. McComb; Elms. James; Faget, Mignon; Faget, Mignon Cressy; Grope, E. Henry; Kraft, Christopher; Grossman, Robert; Allen, Bonnie; Allen, Joe; Barry, John; Clark, Steve; Day, Duane; Mosquera, Jim; Petynia,William; Kobayashi, Herbert Shin; Johnson, Caldwell; Hill, Steve; Carter, Jimmy; Hartman, Charles; Harris, Helen; Kline, Richard; Adornato, Rudolph; Cox, Kenneth J.; Oberg, James; Stoney, William E.; Loftus, Joseph P.; Aleck C. Bond; Young, Arthur; Reagan, Ronald; Johnson, C. C.; Griffin, Gerald D.; Walker, Charlie; Slayton, Donald K.; Slayton, Deke; Huntley, Chet; Crippen, Robert; Cerna, Nanette; Plaxton, Michael; Downs, Hugh; Templeton, Pat; Rathburn, Donald; Drake, Doris; Goddard
Subjects (Organizations)
Space Industries Inc.; United States. Navy; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration; United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics; Space Development Corporation; Thiokol Chemical Corporation. Aerospace Group; Kistler Aerospace Corporation; GB Tech; International Academy of Astronautics; Lockheed Aeronautical Systems Company; National Academy of Engineering; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics; Thiokol; Grumman; Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board; Jet Propulsion Laboratory (U.S.); NPO Energomash imeni akademika V. P. Glushko; Pratt & Whitney Aircraft Company; Rockwell; Arvin Industries; General Electric Company; McDonnell Douglas Aerospace (Firm); United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics; Project Mercury (U.S.); Project Apollo (U.S.); Space Station Freedom Program (U.S.); Hubble Space Telescope (Spacecraft); Soyuz (Organization); International Space Station; Sigma 7; Ranier VII; Voyager I; Puffer (Submarine); SS 414; University of Houston; Manned Spacecraft Center (U.S.); Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center; Hugh L. Dryden Flight Research Center; High School for Engineering Professions
Subjects
Space; Leprosy; Space shuttles; Industrial Space Facility
Places
Antarctica; Louisiana State University and Agricultural and Mechanical College. University College; Belize; British Honduras; London (England); Angel Island (Calif.); Jupiter (Planet); Tokyo, Japan: Asakusa District; USS Prairie State; USSR, 1917-1967; Russia; New Zealand; American Samoa; McMurdo Station (Antarctica); Germany; High School for Engineering Professions
Document Types
Paper; Photographs; Slides; Negatives; Video recordings (physical artifacts); Scrapbooks; Transparencies; Periodicals; Ephemera (general object genre)
Acquisition Information
The Maxime Faget collection was established by a gift from the descendants of Maxime Faget after his death in 2004
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA)
  - Transparencies for Airplane Design, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Large Solid Rocket Original Figures, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Longitudinal Balance Diagram, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - NACA Research Memorandum Flight Tests of a Two Dimensional Wedge Diffuser At Transonic and Super Sonic Speeds, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NACA Report 837 "Standard Nomenclature For Airspeeds with tables and Charts of Airspeed, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NACA Patents with Hand Drawn Diagram of Pressure Ratio Switch, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Confidential NACA Photographs, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NACA Research Memorandum Initial Flight Investigations of a Twin-Engine Supersonic Ram Jet, September 15, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NACA Research Memorandum Initial Flight Investigations of a Twin-Engine Supersonic Ram Jet - Additional Copies, September 15, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Flight Performance of a Twin-Engine Supersonic Ram Jet from 2,300 to 67,200 Feet Altitude, February 19, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Free-Jet Tests of a 6.5-Inch Diameter Ram-Jet Engine at Mach Numbers 1.81 and 2.00, March 7, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Initial Flight Investigations of Twin-Engine Ram-Jet, May 25, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - NACA Charts Adapted from Van Driest's Turbulen Flat-Plate Theory for Determining Values of Turbulent Aerodynamic Friction and Heat-Transfer Coefficients, October 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NACA Similitude Relations for Free-Model Wind-Tunnel Studies of Store-Dropping Problems, January 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - NACA Research Memorandum Preliminary Studies of Manned Satellites, March 18, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Memo Forming Space Task Group at Langley Field, November 5, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Information for Passengers on Inaugural Jet Flight, June 7, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - NACA Reunion II, Williamsburg, Virginia, November 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NACA Reunion IV, San Jose, California, October 1, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NACA Reunion V, October 1820; 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NACA Reunion VI - A Commemorative Album, April 29-May 6, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series II: Mercury
  - Samples of Cord and Parachute Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mercury Era Photographs, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mercury Era Photographs, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Mercury 7 Astronauts Photograph to Faget, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and Newspaper Clippings of Mercury Capsule, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photocopies of Newspaper Clippings of Mercury, July 9, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mercury Escape System Sequence with Sequential Schematic, February/ March 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Clippings of Mercury Pressure Suit, August 10, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mercury Capsule and its Flight Systems, January 25-27, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mercury Capsule and its Flight Systems, April 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Results of the 1st and 2nd U.S. Manned Suborbital Space Flight, June 6, 1961; July 21, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mercury Patents and Monetary Awards Letters, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mercury Inventions Award Letter, December 4, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pictures of MA ( Gordon Cooper, May 1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mercury Program Summary, October 3-4, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mercury Capsule Design including Patents, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Space Capsule Patent Diagram, Small, September 6, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mercury/Apollo Couch Support System, August 13, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mercury 7 Foundation 30th Anniversary of the Flight of Alan Shepherd, May 3, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series III: Apollo
  - Apollo Spacesuit Prototype Photographs, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Astronaut Mission Assignment, 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Apollo Astronaut Official Photographs First through Eighth Manned Missions, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Letters Regarding Project Apollo, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - NASA Anniversary Banquet, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Manned Lunar Mission by Robert Gilruth and Max Faget, July 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Regarding Faget's Congressional Testimony on Apollo, February/ March 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Manned Space Flight Schedule, September 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Black and White Presentation of Apollo CSM/LM on Photo Paper, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Landing and Recovery Scenarios for Apollo, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - EVA Pictures, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Copy of Article for Astronautics and Aeronautics "Apollo-, April 23 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Apollo 1 Review Board Clipping with Photo Schematic of Capsule, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NASA Astronauts Brochure, October 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Letter Dissolving Apollo 204 Review Board, October 16, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Apollo 8 Merry Christmas Napkin, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Apollo 8 Certificate, December 1968/September 4, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Apollo 11 Parade Photographs, August 16, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Apollo 11 Awards Ceremony, October 2, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Apollo 11 Photo of Administrators, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Headline The Moon Decade, December 29, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Moon Photographs, 1969-1970s (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Apollo 14 White House Dinner Invitation with Newspaper Clippings, March 1-2, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - NASA Manned Spacecraft Center Roundup, May 5, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - To the Moon and Beyond by Gilruth, January 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Apollo 16 Prime Crew, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - On the Moon with Apollo 16, April 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Apollo 16 Mission Summary with Photographs, April 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Apollo 17 The Last Apollo, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prints: Apollo 17 The Last Apollo, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Apollo: Image of Patches for Apollo VII to 16 and Image of Apollo from Soyuz, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Background Planning for the Apollo/Soyuz Mission, August 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Evolution of Flight Control of the Apollo Mission, October 5-9, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lunar Landing Gala Celebration 20th Anniversary, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Saturn V Analysis Various Papers on the F-1 Rocket, July 10-12, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 20th Anniversary of Apollo 11 White House Bar-B-Que, July 20, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Apollo F-1 The No Frills Giant, Spring 1992">Spring 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Apollo Command Module: International Historic Mechanical Engineering Landmark, July 24, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Managing the Moon Program: Lessons Learned from Project Apollo, July 1999 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Apollo 11 35th Anniversary Stickers, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Space Shuttle
  - Integral Launch and Reentry Vehicle, August 13, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings Space Shuttle Plans Discussed, October 31, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Space Shuttle Patents, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Artist Rendition of Shuttle Concepts, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Space Shuttle Growth and The Space Shuttle: Papers by Faget, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Orbit Mechanics of Space Shuttle with Handwritten Equations, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Space Shuttle Newspaper Clippings, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Series 4 - Space Shuttle
  - Integral Launch and Reentry Vehicle, August 13, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings Space Shuttle Plans Discussed, October 31, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Space Shuttle Patents, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Artist Rendition of Shuttle Concepts, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Space Shuttle Growth and The Space Shuttle: Papers by Faget, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Orbit Mechanics of Space Shuttle with Handwritten Equations, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Space Shuttle Newspaper Clippings, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Space Shuttle Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Space Shuttle: A New Configuration, January 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Roundup NASA Manner Spacecraft Center, August 14, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Space Shuttle Articles, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fundamental Design Considerations for an Earth-SurfaceTo-Orbit Shuttle, October 4-10, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Early Space Shuttle Patents and Diagrams, November 14, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Space Shuttle Booklet, February 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Space Shuttle Main Engine Design Features, March 1975 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Suborbital Flight Test, May 197[ ] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Space Shuttle Main Engine (SSME) Propellant Flow Schematic, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Space Shuttle Main Engine (SSME) Design Certification Review, April 12, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Space Shuttle Main Engine, May 31, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Astronaut Fact Sheet, October 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Space Shuttle at Work, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - STS-1 Orbiter Final Mission Report, August 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - First Shuttle Achievement Award with Medallion and Performance Bonuses, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Space Shuttle, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New Configuration for Space Shuttle that Provides Suitable Characteristics for Launch, Entry, and Landing, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Aerodynamic Characteristics of Space Shuttle Orbiter, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Space Shuttle by Max Faget, September 26, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Shuttle Presentation Transparencies, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence about Launch of Columbia, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Engineering Analysis of STS-1, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Space Shuttle Space-Enhancing Technological Leadership, Volume 44 Advances in the Astronautical Sciences, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Space Shuttle Houston Post Interview, April 26, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Space Shuttle STS-1 Interim Report, May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Space Shuttle, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Space Shuttle Colombia, June 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Space Shuttle Life Support Systems A Status Report, September 6-12, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Horizontal Water Barrier for STS-2 and All Others, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Space Shuttle Symposium, May 15, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Aerothermodynamic Entry Environment of the Space Shuttle Orbiter, June 7-11, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Space Shuttle Columbia STS-4, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - STS-5 Photograph of Joseph Allen, November 11-15, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - AIAA-83-1485 Effects of Nonequilibrium and Catalysis on Shuttle Heat Transfer, June 1-3, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of STS-1 Astronauts and Mission 51-A, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Space Shuttle Technical Conference, June 28, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - AIAA-84-0574 Von Karman Lecture: The Space Shuttle -, January 9 - (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Space Shuttle Orbiter Data Orbiter Data, circa 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photos of 6" Ball Valve ANSI 2500-1000F and Space Shuttle SRB Joint, May 9, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Testimony to the Subcommittee on Space Sciences and Applications Committee on Science, Space and Technology with Photos, March 23, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - A Docking/Berthing System for Shuttle: Space Industries, January 25, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Crew of STS-40, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Future Space Transportation Based on Shuttle Evolution "FLRB Analysis", September 10, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Comparative Performance Estimations for Shuttle "HLV with (4FT's and 4SSME's) Also, LRB and Hybrid, Files as "Heavy, Magnum, Filed as Rockets), June 3, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Potential Improvements to the Shuttle Through Evolution: Space Industries, June 28-30, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Comparative Performance Estimations for Shuttle "Standard Orbiter LRB(4-F1's) L Booster LRB 4F1, April 7, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Houston Chronicle Cover Story Shuttle Promise Unfulfilled, July 21, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Space Shuttle Orbiter Data Orbiter Data, 1986? (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Photos of 6" Ball Valve ANSI 2500-1000F and Space Shuttle SRB Joint, May 9, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Testimony to the Subcommittee on Space Sciences and Applications Committee on Science, Space and Technology with Photos, March 23, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - A Docking/Berthing System for Shuttle: Space Industries, January 25, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Crew of STS-40, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Future Space Transportation Based on Shuttle Evolution FLRB Analysis, September 10, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Comparative Performance Estimations for Shuttle "HLV with (4FT's and 4SSME's) Also, LRB and Hybrid, Files as "Heavy, Magnum, Filed as Rockets), June 3, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Potential Improvements to the Shuttle Through Evolution: Space Industries, June 28-30, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Comparative Performance Estimations for Shuttle "Standard Orbiter LRB(4-F1's) L Booster LRB 4F1, April 7, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Houston Chronicle Cover Story Shuttle Promise Unfulfilled, July 21, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Series V: Space Station
  - Space Station Freedom Brochure, circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Space Station Freedom: Space Industries Brochure, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Shuttle Derived Space Station Freedom: Space Industries, July 8, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Final Report on Orbiter Derived Space Station Freedom Concept, September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Space Station Plans and Designs, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Space Station Re-Design Meeting, March 15-19, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Trip to Orlando Regarding International Space Station, April 1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Other NASA Materials
  - NASA Space Task Group Directory, Organization, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Changes in Manned Spacecraft Center Basic Organization, January 14, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Map of Manned Spacecraft Center, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Project Outline Maneuverable Television Project (MTV), July 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Engineering Design Study Proposal for Low-Cost, Reliable, and Reusable Space Transportation Vehicle, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - NASA Highlights Brochure, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Space Transportation Main Engine (STME) and Space Transportation Backup Engine (STBE), August 1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - MARS Atmosphere, November 12, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - CASTOR 120TM Motor Product Capabilities and Requirements Document, November 19, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Liquid Flyback Booster Assessment Briefing to Industry, June 15, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - CASTOR 120TM Motor A New Generation, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - An Introduction to Kistler Aerospace Corporation, Summer 1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - GB Tech Employment Letter and X-38 Information, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Various Engine Designs, July 12, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 9 15 Calculations of Return from Payload Delivery Altitude: Diagrams on Motorized Door Opener, August 12, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Scaled Composites, LLC of Space Ship One, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Family of ORBUS Motors ORBUS 21, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - ORBUS Family of Space Propulsion Systems, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - F-1/F01A Progress Report, January 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Thiokol Space Motor Catalog, 1990s? (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - K -1 Review Design Meeting, Meeting #2, September 1, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Kistler Aerospace Brochure and Consultant List, September 11, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Kistler Aerospace K -1 Vehicle Capabilities Summary, July 10, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kistler K -1 Orbiter Vehicle Technical Description, November 24, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series VII: Antarctica, 1966-1967
  - Map of Antarctica, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Narrative: Trip to Antarctica, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Antarctica Photographs, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Antarctica Booklets, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Trip Report - Visit to Antarctica, January 1-11, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Landscape of Antarctic - Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Antarctica Trip - Images of Plane on Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Antarctica: Helicopter, Ice Tunnel Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Antarctica: Faget/Gilruth Beside Lake Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Antarctica: Rock Formations, Eagle Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Antarctica: Helicopter, Ship, Interior Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Antarctica: Interior, Snow Helicopter, Ice Tunnel Slides, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)